{
    "question": "207)  Which  International  Day  is  observed  on  Feb  28/29  to  raise \nawareness about rare diseases and their impacts",
    "answer": "  The World \nRare Disease Day  \n"
}{
    "question": "208)  What was the name of the Joint Airforce exercise of India and \nUK held in last week of February",
    "answer": " Exercise Indradhanush 2020 \n"
}{
    "question": "209)  Exercise Indradhanush 2020 was held at which place in India",
    "answer": " \nAir Force Station Hindan, near Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "210)  Which apex organization has recently launched \"UPI Chalega\" \ncampaign to promote UPI as easy, safe, and instant mode of \npayment",
    "answer": "   National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) \n"
}{
    "question": "211)  Which film won the best film award at the Dadasaheb Phalke \nInternational Film Festival Awards 2020",
    "answer": " Super 30 \n"
}{
    "question": "212)  Who is the director of the award winning film Super 30",
    "answer": " Vikash \nBahl  \n"
}{
    "question": "213)  Name  the  five-time  Grand  Slam  winner  tennis  player  from \nRussia, one of the highest-paid sportswomen for 11 years, who \nannounced her retirement",
    "answer": " Maria Sharapova  \n"
}{
    "question": "215)  What is the full form of the MSMED Act, 2006",
    "answer": " Micro, Small \nand Medium Enterprises Development  \n"
}{
    "question": "217)  The 6th National Ice Stock Sports Championship was held  at \nwhich place",
    "answer": " Gulmarg (J & K) \n"
}{
    "question": "218)  Mohammed  Hosni  Mubarak, who died recently, ruled  which \ncountry as President for 30 years",
    "answer": " Egypt \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  137 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "219)  US President Donald Trump was given a grand public reception \nat which stadium in Ahmedabad",
    "answer": " Sardar Patel Stadium, Motera \n"
}{
    "question": "220)  During his India visit, US President signed a $3 billion deal to \nsupply which helicopters to India",
    "answer": " MH-60 Romeo Helicopters \n"
}{
    "question": "221)  What type of helicopters are the MH-60 Romeo Helicopters",
    "answer": " \nAdvanced anti-submarine and anti-surface warfare helicopter  \n"
}{
    "question": "222)  ndia celebrates Central Excise Day on which date",
    "answer": " February 24 \n"
}{
    "question": "223)  What is the name of the Hindi version of Artificial Intelligence-\nbased chatbot launched by the Indian Railway",
    "answer": " ASKDISHA \n"
}{
    "question": "224)  __________ has become the first Indian Football Club to qualify \nfor the Asian Football Confederation (AFC) Champions League \ngroup stage",
    "answer": " FC Goa \n"
}{
    "question": "225)  India\u2019s first floating jetty has been inaugurated at which place \nin Goa",
    "answer": " Vasco \n"
}{
    "question": "227)  India celebrates National Science Day on February 28 to honour \nthe scientific  achievement  of which  Nobel  laureate",
    "answer": "  Sir C V \nRaman \n"
}{
    "question": "228)  What is the popular name of the discovery made by Sir C V \nRaman for which he was awarded the Nobel prize in Physics in \n1930",
    "answer": " Raman Effect \n"
}{
    "question": "229)  D Gukesh, the 13-year old ChessGrandmaster from Tamil Nadu \nemerged champion in the 34th Cannes Open in which country",
    "answer": " \nFrance  \n"
}{
    "question": "230)  According to the Commerce Ministry data for 2018-19, which \ncountry was India's top trading partner",
    "answer": " USA \n"
}{
    "question": "233)  What is the name of the autobiography of Yashwant Sinha, \nveteran  BJP  leader  and  former  Minister  of  Finance  and \nExternal Affairs",
    "answer": " Relentless  \n"
}{
    "question": "234)  What is the title of the recent book written by Jaggi Vasudev, \npopular as \u2018Sadhguru\u2019, noted Yogi and spiritual leader",
    "answer": " Death- \nAn Inside Story \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  138 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "235)   'Amnesty' is a popular novel written by which author",
    "answer": " Aravind \nAdiga \n"
}{
    "question": "236)  What is the title of the new novel of Colum McCann released in \nFebruary 2020",
    "answer": " Apeirogon \n"
}{
    "question": "237)  Which two Union Territories recently hosted the Khelo India \nWinter Games 2020",
    "answer": " Ladakh and J&K  \n"
}{
    "question": "238)  As per the Sustainability Index 2020 brought out by the World \nHealth Organization (WHO), UN Children\u2019s Fund (UNICEF) \nand the Lancet medical journal, India has been ranked at which \nplace",
    "answer": " 77th \n"
}{
    "question": "239)  Who  has  been  appointed  as  per  the  new  Central  Vigilance \nCommissioner - CVC of India",
    "answer": "  Sanjay Kothari \n"
}{
    "question": "240)  The Northeast Frontier Railway Construction Organisation has \nbuilt India\u2019s tallest railway pier bridge \u2014 100 m tall in which \nstate",
    "answer": " Manipur \n"
}{
    "question": "242)  Divya Kakran  won gold  in the 68  kg  category  in  an  Asian \nchampionship in which sports",
    "answer": " Wrestling   \n"
}{
    "question": "243)  ESPN Sports Awards are given by which organization",
    "answer": "  ESPN \nTV Network, USA   \n"
}{
    "question": "244)  What  is  the  full  form  of  ESPN",
    "answer": "  Entertainment  and  Sports \nProgramming Network \n"
}{
    "question": "247)  Which day is celebrated across the globe with support from \nUNESCO, Paris to celebrate the linguistic diversity that exists \nin the world",
    "answer": " International Mother Language Day, Feb 21 \n"
}{
    "question": "248)  What  is  the  theme  for  this  year's  International  Mother \nLanguage Day",
    "answer": " Languages without borders \n"
}{
    "question": "249)  The  World  Social  Justice  Day  is  observed  on  Feb  20  with \nsupport  from  which  UN  organization",
    "answer": "  International  Labour \nOrganization, Geneva \n"
}{
    "question": "250)  Indian  Railways  Catering  and  Tourism  Corporation  recently \nannounced  to run  a special  tourist train  covering  important \nplaces linked with Lord Rama What is its name",
    "answer": " Sri Ramayana \nExpress  \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  139 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "251)  Which National Day is celebrated to commemorate the launch \nof the Soil Health Card Scheme  in 2015",
    "answer": " Soil Health Card Day, \nFeb 19  \n"
}{
    "question": "252)  Which zone of the Indian Railways has become the 1st zonal \nrailway  in  the  country  to  have  functional  \u201cenergy  neutral\u201d \nrailway stations",
    "answer": " South Central Railway Zone, Secunderabad \n"
}{
    "question": "253)  Which global finance agency has agreed to give a $450 million \nloan to promote Atal Bhujal Yojana",
    "answer": " World Bank \n"
}{
    "question": "254)  The 3rd edition of the Global Ministerial Conference on Road \nSafety  was  held  in  capital  of  which  country",
    "answer": "  Sweden \n(Stockholm) \n"
}{
    "question": "255)  Name the corporate businessman who recently secured second \nrank in the list of richest persons of India",
    "answer": " Radhakishan Damani  \n"
}{
    "question": "256)  What is the popular name of the retail super market chain being \nrun by Damani",
    "answer": " D-Mart  \n"
}{
    "question": "257)   What is the official motto of the Tokyo 2020 Olympics",
    "answer": " United \nby Emotion \n"
}{
    "question": "258)  The International Hockey Federation has granted hosting rights \nfor the Junior Men\u2019s Hockey World Cup 2021 to which country",
    "answer": " \nIndia \n"
}{
    "question": "260)  Which International Airport in India was recently declared free \nfrom   single-use  plastic  usage",
    "answer": "  Delhi's  Indira  Gandhi \nInternational Airport \n"
}{
    "question": "261)  Koneru Humpy claimed her second title in the last two months \nby winning which tournament",
    "answer": "  Cairns Cup chess tournament, \nUSA \n"
}{
    "question": "262)  The  Laureus  World  Sports  Awards  -  2020  were  announced \nrecently at which place",
    "answer": " Berlin, Germany  \n"
}{
    "question": "264)  Who  is  Simone  Biles,  winner  of  this  year's  Laureus \nSportswoman of the year award",
    "answer": " Star Gymnast with highest ever \nnumber of Olympic and World Championship medals \n"
}{
    "question": "265)  Which state government has declared the Cauvery delta region \nas a Protected Special Agriculture Zone",
    "answer": " Tamil Nadu  \n"
}{
    "question": "267)  Which Indian city hosted the 65th Filmfare Awards",
    "answer": " Guwahati  \n"
}{
    "question": "268)  Which film won the Filmfare Award for the Best Film",
    "answer": " Gully \nBoy  \n"
}{
    "question": "271)  Who has been re-elected as the President of Afghanistan",
    "answer": " Ashraf \nGhani  \n"
}{
    "question": "272)  Debasish Panda has been appointed to which important post in \nthe Ministry of Finance",
    "answer": " Finance Secretary   \n"
}{
    "question": "273)  The famous Dan David Prize is supported by which university",
    "answer": " \nTel Aviv University, Israel \n"
}{
    "question": "274)  Who won the men's singles title at the 77th Senior National \nSquash Championship held in Chennai",
    "answer": " Saurav Ghosal \n"
}{
    "question": "275)  The women's singles title at the 77th Senior National Squash \nChampionship was won by which player",
    "answer": " Joshna Chinappa  \n"
}{
    "question": "276)  World SnowShoe Championships were recently held in which \ncountry",
    "answer": " Japan \n"
}{
    "question": "277)  The 13th Conference of Parties (COP) of the Convention on the \nConservation of Migratory Species of Wild Animals was hosted \nby which city",
    "answer": "  Gandhinagar, Gujarat \n"
}{
    "question": "278)  Which animal / bird has been named as the mascot of the above \nevent",
    "answer": " Gibi - The Great Indian Bustard \n"
}{
    "question": "279)  Supreme Court directed the union government to grant _____  \ncommission to all women officers who opt for it",
    "answer": " Permanent  \n"
}{
    "question": "281)  The external affairs ministry has decided to rename the Pravasi \nBhartiya  Kendra  and  Foreign  Service  Institute  after  which \nveteran political leader",
    "answer": " Late Sushma Swaraj  \n"
}{
    "question": "282)  The  central  government  launched  the  \u201cSchool  Health \nAmbassador Initiative\u201d for what purpose",
    "answer": " To spread awareness \nabout the preventive health aspects \n"
}{
    "question": "283)  The \u201cSchool Health Ambassador Initiative\u201d has been launched \nas a part of which bigger programme",
    "answer": " Ayushman Bharat \n"
}{
    "question": "284)  India celebrates national women's day on Feb 13 in the honour \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  141 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nof which great woman leader",
    "answer": " Sarojini Naidu  \n"
}{
    "question": "285)  On  account  of  her  excellence  in  poetry,  Sarojini  Naidu  was \nknown will which nick name",
    "answer": "  Bharat Kokila (Nightingale of \nIndia) \n"
}{
    "question": "286)  Which  state  hosted  \u201cClimFishCon  2020\u201d,  a  four  day \ninternational conference on the impact of climate change on \n\u2018hydrological  cycle,  ecosystem,  fisheries  and  food  security",
    "answer": " \nKerala  \n"
}{
    "question": "287)  The seven nation BIMSTEC Disaster Management Exercise - \n2020  was  hosted  by  the  National  Disaster  Response  Force \n(NDRF) in which city",
    "answer": " Bhubaneswar, Odisha \n"
}{
    "question": "288)  What is the full form of the acronym BIMSTEC",
    "answer": " Bay of Bengal \nInitiative for Multi-Sectoral Technical and Economic Cooperation \n"
}{
    "question": "289)  Headquarters  of  the  BIMSTEC  are  located  in  which  city",
    "answer": " \nDhaka, Bangladesh \n"
}{
    "question": "290)  President Ram Nath Kovind presented \u2018President\u2019s Colour\u2019 to \nthe  INS  Shivaji  It  is  located  at  which  place",
    "answer": "  Lonavala, \nMaharashtra \n"
}{
    "question": "291)  What type of naval establishment is INS Shivaji",
    "answer": "  It houses \nNaval College of Engineering \n"
}{
    "question": "292)  What  is  the  name  200-km  strike  range  supersonic  tactical \nballistic missile being developed by DRDO",
    "answer": " Pranash  \n"
}{
    "question": "293)  Supported by UNESCO, the World Radio Day is observed on \nwhich date",
    "answer": " Feb 13 \n"
}{
    "question": "294)  What is the theme of this year's World Radio Day",
    "answer": " Radio and \nDiversity \n"
}{
    "question": "295)  The  National  Property  Day  celebrations  on  Feb  12  are \npromoted by which Union Ministry",
    "answer": " Ministry of Commerce and \nIndustry  \n"
}{
    "question": "296)  Name the noted environmentalist, former chief and founder of \nTERI (The Energy and Resources Institute), New Delhi, who \npassed away recently",
    "answer": " Dr R K Pachauri \n"
}{
    "question": "298)  Which Indian player was named Player of the Year for 2019 by \nthe International Hockey Federation",
    "answer": " Manrpreet Singh \n"
}{
    "question": "300)  AAP Chief Arvind Kejriwal secured a landslide victory in Delhi \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  142 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nassembly elections, becoming Chief Minster for the ________ \ntime",
    "answer": " 3rd \n"
}{
    "question": "301)  According  to  the  PSU  Survey  2018-19,  which  PSUs  is  the \nhighest  profit  earning  organisation",
    "answer": "    Oil  and  Natural  Gas \nCorporation (ONGC) \n"
}{
    "question": "302)  Name the cueist who defeated multiple-time world champion \nPankaj Advani 6-2 to win the National Snooker Championship \nin Pune",
    "answer": " Aditya Mehta  \n"
}{
    "question": "303)  Who is the current national title holder of women's and snooker",
    "answer": " \nVidya Pillai  \n"
}{
    "question": "305)  Ajeya Warrior-2020:  5th edition of joint military exercise of \nIndia was held with which other country",
    "answer": " United Kingdom   \n"
}{
    "question": "306)  The IOC Coaches Lifetime Achievement Awards for Men has \nbeen won by whom",
    "answer": " Malcolm Arnold from Uganda, for training \nathletes \n"
}{
    "question": "307)  Who  won  the  women's  IOC  Coaches  Lifetime  Achievement \nAward",
    "answer": " Ulla Koch from Germany, for training  gymnasts \n"
}{
    "question": "308)  Where in India a glass floor suspension bridge, the first of its \nkind  in  the  country,  is  to  be  constructed",
    "answer": "  Rishikesh, \nUttarakhand  \n"
}{
    "question": "311)  The roots of Unani medicine system can be traced to which \nmodern country",
    "answer": " Greece  \n"
}{
    "question": "312)  India celebrates Unani Day on which date",
    "answer": " Feb 11 \n"
}{
    "question": "313)  The Kolkata-based Garden Reach Shipbuilders and Engineers \ndelivered \u201cINS Kavaratti\u201d to the Indian navy recently What \ntype of ship it is",
    "answer": " Anti-submarine warfare stealth corvette \n"
}{
    "question": "314)  African Union Summit 2020 was held on Feb 10-11 in which \nplace",
    "answer": " Addis Ababa, Ethiopia  \n"
}{
    "question": "315)  Who  is  Cyril  Ramaphosa,  the  current  chairman  of  African \nUnion",
    "answer": " President of South Africa   \n"
}{
    "question": "316)  Which Indian badminton coach, was awarded an \"honourable \nmention\" at the IOC Coaches Lifetime Achievement Awards \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  143 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n2019",
    "answer": " Pullela Gopichand \n"
}{
    "question": "317)  Which  state  won  the  10th  Hockey  India  Senior  Women \nNational  Championship  2020  (A  Division)  title  at  Kollam, \nKerala",
    "answer": " Haryana   \n"
}{
    "question": "319)  What is the popular name for the prestigious Academy Awards \ngiven for outstanding excellence in cinema",
    "answer": " Oscar  \n"
}{
    "question": "320)  Who made the documentary American Factory, the film that \nwon the Oscar for the best documentary",
    "answer": " Barack and Michelle \nObama  \n"
}{
    "question": "321)  Name the South Korean director, who won the Oscar for the \nbest director for the film Parasite",
    "answer": " Bong Joon-ho  \n"
}{
    "question": "323)  The  largest  exhibition  for  the  world's  defence  companies  to \ndisplay their land, sea and air capabilities was held at which city \nin India",
    "answer": " Lucknow, UP  \n"
}{
    "question": "324)  _________ of Sri Lanka, Mahinda Rajapaksa, arrived in New \nDelhi  on Feb 8 on a five day state visit",
    "answer": " Prime Minister  \n"
}{
    "question": "325)  Which Union Ministry organises the National Deworming Day \non Feb 10",
    "answer": " Ministry of Health and Family Welfare \n"
}{
    "question": "326)  Which medicine is administered to the children on the National \nDeworming Day",
    "answer": " Albendazole \n"
}{
    "question": "327)  Who created three new records in the men's 109kg category in \nthe  National  Weightlifting  Championships  at  Kolkata",
    "answer": " \nChandrakant Mali \n"
}{
    "question": "328)  The  International  Intellectual  Property  (IP)  Index  which \nmeasures the intellectual property environment of 53 economies \nof the world, placed India at which rank",
    "answer": " 40th \n"
}{
    "question": "329)  Britain's  Prince  Charles unveiled a  new  children's  protection \nfund for which country as part of British Asian Trust",
    "answer": " India \n"
}{
    "question": "330)  India replaced which country to become 2nd largest producer of \nsteel in the world in 2019",
    "answer": " Japan  \n"
}{
    "question": "331)  Which country is the largest producer of steel in the world",
    "answer": " \nChina \n"
}{
    "question": "332)   Who has been awarded the International Gandhi Awards for \nLeprosy",
    "answer": " Dr NS Dharmashaktu \n"
}{
    "question": "333)  Name the longest-serving Kenyan President, who passed away \non February 04",
    "answer": " Daniel Arap Moi \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  144 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "334)   India\u2019s  biggest  rural  technical  festival  titled  \u2018Antahpragnya \n2020\u2019  was  held  in  Rajiv  Gandhi  University  of  Knowledge \nTechnologies, in which state",
    "answer": " Telangana  \n"
}{
    "question": "336)  Ajay Bisaria has been appointed as the next High Commissioner \nof India to which country",
    "answer": " Canada  \n"
}{
    "question": "337)  The Indian Navy conducted a coastal security exercise named \n\u2018Malta Abhiyan\u2019 in which place",
    "answer": " Sunderban delta waters near \nKolkata, West Bengal  \n"
}{
    "question": "339)  Which country has introduced a new system for collecting fee \nfrom regional  tourists,  called \u2018Sustainable Development  Fee",
    "answer": " \nBhutan   \n"
}{
    "question": "340)  Which  cinema  award  are  popularly  known  as  the  Oscars  of \nEurope",
    "answer": "  BAFTA Awards  \n"
}{
    "question": "341)  What is the full form of BAFTA",
    "answer": " British Academy Film and \nTelevision Arts \n"
}{
    "question": "342)  Which film secured the BAFTA award for the best film",
    "answer": "  1917 \nby Sam Mendes \n"
}{
    "question": "343)  Who won the BAFTA award for the best leading actress",
    "answer": " Renee \nZellweger (Judy) \n"
}{
    "question": "344)  Name the actor who won all the three top global awards viz \nOscar, Golden Globe and BAFTA for the best actor",
    "answer": " Joaquin \nPhoenix (Joker)  \n"
}{
    "question": "346)  The  Insurance  cover  on  the  bank  deposits  of  individuals  is \nprovided by which RBI owned company",
    "answer": " Deposit Insurance and \nCredit Guarantee Corporation (DICGC),  \n"
}{
    "question": "347)  Which  International  Day  is  celebrated  on  Feb  2  to  raise \nawareness about the importance of  wetlands in maintaining \necological balance",
    "answer": " World Wetland Day  \n"
}{
    "question": "348)  Which  Island  country  recently  re-joined  the  commonwealth, \nafter having left in 2016",
    "answer": " Maldives  \n"
}{
    "question": "349)  What is the number of member countries of the Commonwealth \nafter joining of Maldives",
    "answer": " 54 \n"
}{
    "question": "350)  Who has been chosen as the \u201cCentral Banker of the Year\u201d for \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  145 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nthe Asia Pacific Region by  the London based global financial \nmagazine - The Banker",
    "answer": " Shaktikanta Das \n"
}{
    "question": "351)  What is the theme of this year's World Cancer Day observed on \nFeb 04",
    "answer": " \"I am and I will\"  \n"
}{
    "question": "353)  The Gram Nyayalayas are to be established under the provision \nof which law",
    "answer": " Gram Nyayalayas Act, 2008  \n"
}{
    "question": "354)  Which global technology giant announced a dollar one million \ngrant to promote news literacy among Indians",
    "answer": " Google  \n"
}{
    "question": "355)  10th Hockey India Senior Men National Championship was held \nat which place",
    "answer": " Jhansi, UP \n"
}{
    "question": "356)  Mary Higgins Clark, the long-reigning \"Queen of Suspense\", one \nof the world's most popular writers, died recently She hailed \nfrom which country",
    "answer": " USA \n"
}{
    "question": "357)  Name the former communication minister of Iraq who has been \nappointed as the Prime Minister of Iraq",
    "answer": " Mohammad Allawi \n"
}{
    "question": "358)  India and which other country held the 14 day joint military \ntraining exercise SAMPRITI-IX",
    "answer": " Bangladesh  \n"
}{
    "question": "359)  The  bilateral  military  exercise  SAMPRITI-IX  was  held  at \nwhich place",
    "answer": "  Umroi, Meghalaya  \n"
}{
    "question": "361)  What is the name of the flame-throated Bulbul, that has been \nunveiled as the official mascot for the Games",
    "answer": " Rubigula  \n"
}{
    "question": "362)  The finals of the first grand slam of the year Australian Open \nwere held in which city",
    "answer": " Melbourne  \n"
}{
    "question": "363)  Who won her first grand slam title by winning the Australian \nOpen",
    "answer": " Sofia Kenin, USA   \n"
}{
    "question": "364)  Men's Singles title in the Australian Open was won by which \nplayer",
    "answer": " Novak Djokovic, Serbia  \n"
}{
    "question": "365)  Which state bagged the first position for the implementation of \nPradhan Mantri Matru Vandana Yojana",
    "answer": " Madhya Pradesh  \n"
}{
    "question": "367)  Name  the  British  political  leader  who  successfully  led  the \nBritain's exit plan from the European  Union",
    "answer": " Boris Johnson  \n"
}{
    "question": "368)  Billed as the world\u2019s largest meditation facility, an imposing \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  146 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nmeditation  centre  was  inaugurated  in  \u2018Kanha  Shantivanam\u2019 \nnear which city",
    "answer": " Hyderabad \n"
}{
    "question": "369)  Which  country  created  a  new  Guinness  World  Record  for \norganizing  the  highest  altitude  Fashion  Show  on  the  earth",
    "answer": " \nNepal  \n"
}{
    "question": "370)  President Ram Nath Kovind inaugurated the 34th Surajkund \nInternational Crafts Fair on February 1 at Surajkund in which \nplace",
    "answer": " Faridabad, Haryana \n"
}{
    "question": "371)  Which  was  the  partner  country  for  this  year's  Surajkund \nInternational Crafts Fair",
    "answer": "   Uzbekistan \n"
}{
    "question": "372)   Which player won the prestigious 'World Games Athlete of the \nYear'  award  given  by  the  International  World  Games \nAssociation",
    "answer": "  Rani Rampal \n"
}{
    "question": "373)   Who is Rani Rampal",
    "answer": "   Captain of Indian Women's Hockey \nTeam \n"
}{
    "question": "374)  Tyler  Prize,  often  described  as  the  \u2018Nobel  Prize  for \nEnvironment\u2019 was awarded to whom this year",
    "answer": " Pawan Sukhdev \n"
}{
    "question": "375)  Who has been elected as the Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of \nthe  Indian  Banks\u2019  Association  (IBA),  Mumbai  for  the  year \n2020",
    "answer": " Sunil Mehta  \n"
}{
    "question": "376)  Which state launched a virtual police station where people can \nlodge complaints online from their respective districts,  without \nvisiting the Police Station",
    "answer": " Odisha  \n"
}{
    "question": "377)  Oxford  University  Press  named  which  word  as  the  \u201cOxford \nHindi Word of 2019\u201d saying it received widespread attention in \nthe year",
    "answer": " Samvidhaan (Constitution) \n"
}{
    "question": "378)  Esow Alben of India is a leading sports star of which sports",
    "answer": " \nCycling \n"
}{
    "question": "379)  Taranjit  Singh  Sandhu, 1988  batch  IFS  officer  has  been \nappointed as India\u2019s ambassador to which country",
    "answer": " USA   "
}